## Roman Sypchenko

rs.sypchenko@gmail.com | 403-200-8512 | Calgary, AB, Canada | www.linkedin.com/in/sypchenko

## **SUMMARY**

Frontend developer with 7+ years of experience leveraging JavaScript to build responsive websites and interactive features that drive business growth and improve UX. Collaborated with both large and small teams. Have a solid knowledge of modern frontend stack and application architecture.

#### **SKILLS**

JavaScript, React.js, Vue.js, jQuery, Redux, React Hooks, React Router, Styled Components, Next.js, GraphQL, TypeScript, HTML, CSS, SASS, LESS, Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap, Figma, Git, Webpack, Gulp, Docker, Jest, Cypress, Node.js, Express, MongoDB.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

**AUTO1 Group (Europe's leading digital automotive platform)**, Germany **JavaScript Engineer**, Remote

Dec 2021 - Nov 2022

Build financing tools for large-scale micro-frontend project

- Moved legacy code to new micro-frontend architecture using React.js, TypeScript, GraphQL
- Collaborated with QA team to improve quality of existing components and covered more components by autotests and added more use-cases
- Developed and improved 10+ existing and new reusable components for a custom UI library
- Developed new financing tools and UI features for Backoffice

**Tech stack**: React.js, React Hooks, React Hooks Form, Next.js, GraphQL, TypeScript, Apollo, Docker, Jest, LESS, HTML, Jenkins, Git, Apollo, GitHub.

# **Everest Media (Affiliate network),** Montenegro **Senior Frontend Developer**

Aug 2020 – Dec 2021

Build and designed e-commerce projects

- Led company to use templates and building tools with an internal framework for custom e-commerce shops that reduce page load time by more than 50% and increase the speed of development
- Designed and Implemented an internal framework that increased development speed by 25%
- Mentored a team of 5 front-end developers to improve their technical and soft skills increased the speed and code quality of project development
- Involved in hiring pipeline: CV screening, interviewing candidates, evaluating tech assessments.

**Tech stack**: javaScript, React.js, Vue.js, Docker, Webpack, Gulp, Node.js, Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap, Cypress, Jest, SASS, HTML, GitLab.

## Finline, Ukraine

Oct 2016 – Aug 2020

### **Frontend Developer**

Build from scratch financing projects (Education platform, Crypto platform)

- Developed UI for a crypto platform that allowed analysis using charts and graphic tools for buying and selling stock and crypto assets
- Designed and developed a visual editor (UML) that allowed auto setup and configure servers and traffic distribution
- Designed and developed an education platform for financing and crypto traders.

**Tech stack**: React.js, Vue.js, Docker, Jest, Charts.js, Node.js, Bootstrap.

## Finline, Ukraine

Aug 2014 – Oct 2016

## **Frontend Developer**

- Developed and maintained Backoffice and UI tools for our clients that increased the quality of service and product support
- Designed and developed Web Chat for the support team that allows our client quickly solve issues and get better service

Tech stack: JQuery, CSS, SCSS, SASS, HTML, Chart.js, Bootstrap, Semantic UI

# **EDUCATION**

**Alfred Nobel University,** Dnipro, Ukraine Bachelor's degree in Computer Science

Sep 2008 – Jun 2012